Guide to the Extra-illustrated Life of Nollekens
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Windsor. Plate 7 engraved by Wm. & J Walker, from an original drawing by T. Girtin. Published May 1st 1792 by Harrison & Co. No. 18, Paternoster Row, London., 1792 May 1; engraving; 20.5 x 28 cm. (Box 1-157)
  View of Windsor.
  Engravings; Windsor Castle
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., undated; Ollier, Charles, 1788-1859; 1 page; 25 x 20 cm. (Box 1-158)
  Introducing Mr. Radcliffe 'who wishes to speak to you about the anecdotes of his late wife which you have introduced in your memoir of Nollekens and his times'. Maida Vale, Wednesday.
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833
- Letter to 'Gentlemen'., undated; Seward, William, 1747-1799; 1 pages; 20.5 x 14 cm. (Box 1-159)
  About a publication and presumably written to publishers. 'I shall require only fifty copies of it..."
- Thomas Howard, Earl of Arundel and Surrey. From the original of Rubens, in the Collection of the Righ. Honble. The Earl of Warwick. Drawn by W. Hilton A.R. A. and engraved (with permission) by E. Scriven. London. Published Septr. 1 1917 by Lackington, Hughes, Harding, Mavor & Jones and Longman, Hurst, Rees, Orme & Brown., 1817 September 1; engraving; 31 x 24 cm. (Box 1-160)
  Portrait of Thomas Howard Earl of Arundel.
  Engravings; Arundel, Thomas Howard, Earl of, 1585-1646
- Westminster from Vauxhall. Drawn by S. Prout. Geo. Cooke 1827., engraving; 24 x 30 cm. (Box 1-161)
  View of Westminster.
  Westminster (London, England); Engravings; Westminster Abbey
- Henry 7th's Chapel, North Front of Westminster Abbey, Westminster from Lambeth, West Cloister, East Cloister. Drawn by H. West, engraved by J. Shury, London, Published by W.S. Orr 1833., engraving; 21.5 x 12.5 cm. (Box 1-162)
  Five views of Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Westminster Abbey; Henry VII's Chapel (Westminster Abbey)
- Geoffrey Chaucer. In the collection of Sir Hans Sloane Bart. J. Houbraken sculps. Amst. 1741. Impensis I. & P. Knapton Londini 1742., engraving; 38 x 24 cm. (Box 1-167)
  Portrait of Geoffrey Chaucer.
  Engravings; Chaucer, Geoffrey, -1400
- New-gate., undated; engraving; 13 x 9 cm. (Box 1-169)
- Frederick Prince of Wales. Ravenet sculp., undated; engraving; 10.5 x 10.5 cm. (Box 1-171)
  Portrait of Frederick Louis, Prince of Wales.
  Engravings; Frederick Louis, Prince of Wales, 1707-1751
- Untitled portrait of Richard Grosvenor., engraving; 20 x 15 cm. (Box 1-179)
  Engravings; Grosvenor, Richard Grosvenor, Earl, 1731-1802
- Printed ticket, completed in manuscript: "Admit Mrs. Young & three to view the pictures at Grosvenor House on Friday the 7th June, from 12 till 5 o'clock." Signed: "Grosvenor"., undated; Grosvenor, Richard Grosvenor, Earl, 1731-1802; ticket; 8 x 12 cm. (Box 1-179)
  Tickets
- William Hogarth from an original picture painted by himself. Engraved by S. Freeman. Jones & Co. Temple of the Muses, Finsbury Square, London., undated; engraving; 22.5 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1-180)
  Portrait of William Hogarth.
  Engravings; Hogarth, William, 1697-1764
- Industry and Idleness. Plate 8. The Industrious 'Prentice Grown Rich, and Sheriff of London. From the original design by Hogarth. Engraved by C. Armstrong. Jones & Co. Temple of the Muses Finsbury Square, London., undated; engraving; 19 x 22.5 cm. (Box 1-181)
- Industry and Idleness. Plate 7. The Idle 'Prentice Returned from Sea, and in a Garret with a Prostitute. From the original design by Hogarth. Engraved by E. Jordan. Jones & Co. Temple of the Muses, Finsbury Square, London., undated; engraving; 19.5 x 22.5 cm. (Box 1-181)
- Gog & Magog. Guildhall. European Magazine. Publish'd by I. Asperme at the Bible, Crown & Constitution, Cornhill, Sept. 1, 1810., 1810 September 1; engraving; 11 x 17 cm. (Box 1-183)
- Untitled depiction of Hercules strangling the lion. Thos. Worlidge fecit 1757., etching; 10 x 8 cm. (Box 1-183)
- Untitled portrait of Paul A. Rubens. Art. Van Dyck pinx. Ficquet sculp. Eissen Oct., undated; engraving; 7 x 10 cm. (Box 1-186)
  Engravings; Rubens, Paul A. (Paul Alfred), 1875-1917
- Sir William Beechey, R.A. From an original picture by himself in his own possession. Drawn by W. Evans, engraved by R. Cooper. Published June 11 1814 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1814 June 11; engraving; 31 x 24.5 cm. (Box 1-188)
  Portrait of Sir William Beechey.
  Engravings; Beechey, William, Sir, 1753-1839
- Untitled portrait of Samuel Ireland. Js. Gy. fec. Pubd. Decr. 1st, 1797, by H. Humphrey, no. 27 St. James's Street, London., 1797 December 1; engraving; 31 x 23.5 cm. (Box 1-195)
  Engravings; Ireland, Samuel, d. 1800
- Thomas Britton. Small-Coal-Man. I. Woolaston pinxit. C. Grignion sculpsit., undated; engraving; 14 x 13 cm. (Box 1-198)
  Portrait of Thomas Britton.
  Engravings; Britton, Thomas, 1654?-1714
- Mr. Shuter in the character of Justice Woodcock in Love in a Village, Act I. Scene 6th. Printed for Rt. Sayer, No. 53 Fleet Street & J. Smith No. 35 in Cheapside, 20 December 1769., 1769 December 20; engraving; 9 x 7.5 cm. (Box 1-199)
  Portrait of Edward Shuter.
  Engravings; Shuter, Edward, 1728?-1776
- Newcastle House, Lincoln's Inn Fields. B. Howlet fccit G. Scharf. Lithog., undated; lithograph; 16 x 22.5 cm. (Box 1-202)
  View of Newcastle House, Lincoln's Inn Fields.
- Sir Godfrey Kneller, Bart. Cooper sculpt., undated; engraving; 30 x 23 cm. (Box 1-203)
  Portrait of Sir Godfrey Kneller.
  Engravings; Kneller, Godfrey, Sir, 1646-1723
- Right Honble. Lady Thurlow., engraving; 16 x 11 cm. (Box 1-205)
  Portrait of Mary Catherine Thurlow.
  Engravings; Thurlow, Mary Catherine, 1790-1830
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1808 April 27; Hawkins, Laetitia Matilda, 1759-1835; 1 page; 18 x 11 cm. (Box 1-211)
  Asking him to have a 'little parcel' ready for collection by 9:30 a.m. Monday so that it can be collected. Twickenham, 27 April.
- Chas. Hutton. W. Derby delt. J. Thomson sct. London, Published for the proprietors of the European Magazine by Lupston Relfe, 13 Corhill, July 1, 1823., 1823 July 1; engraving; 20 x 13.5 cm. (Box 1-212)
  Portrait of Charles Hutton.
  Engravings; Hutton, Charles, 1737-1823
- William Gifford, Esq. Wm. Gifford [facsimile signature] Painted by J. Hoppner, Esq. R.A. Engraved by S. Freeman. Fisher, Son & Co. London, 1833., engraving; 21 x 14 cm. (Box 1-212)
  Portrait of William Gifford.
  Engravings; Gifford, William, 1756-1826
- Prince Hoare Esqr. Opie pinxt. Hopwood sculp. Published 1 July 1807 by Mathews & Leigh., 1807 July 1; engraving; 19.5 x 12 cm. (Box 1-214)
  Portrait of Prince Hoare.
  Engravings; Hoare, Prince, 1755-1834
- Punch and Judy. Scenes of London. On Stone by G. Rymer, London published by Ackermann & Co. 96, Strand, Sepr. 1st 1834., 1834 September 1; etching; 20 x 24.5 cm. (Box 1-217)
  Punch and Judy; Lithographs
- Letter to Mr. Smith., undated; Gower, C., Dr.; 1 page; 23 x 18.5 cm. (Box 1-222)
  Telling Mr. Smith that Mr. Haslam, apothecary at Bethle Hospital, will allow him to visit the patients there 'in a private manner' so he can draw them. The visit '...will give you a thorough knowledge of character, and enable you to give a justness to the sketches you may draw...be sure you pocket your pencil...The Imperial King [an inmate] is a fine study, and will make an excellent picture...'. Sunday.
  Correspondence; Bethlem Royal Hospital (London, England)
- Caius Gabriel Cibber. W. C. Edwards., undated; engraving; 13.5 x 10 cm. (Box 1-222)
  Portrait of Caius Gabriel Cibber.
  Engravings; Cibber, Caius Gabriel, 1630-1700
- Figures in front of Bethlem Hospital. Engraved by C. Warren. For Dr. Hughsons Description of London. Published by J. Stratford, 112 Holborn Hill, Decr. 10th, 1808., 1808 December 10; engraving; 12.5 x 19 cm. (Box 1-222)
  View of figures in front of Bethlem Hospital.
  Engravings; Bethlem Royal Hospital (London, England)
- John Opie Esqr. R.A. J. Opie R.A. pinx Ridley sc. Pub. by Vernor & Hood Poultry Aug. 1 1801., 1801 August 1; engraving; 29 x 22.5 (Box 1-223)
  Portrait of John Opie.
  Engravings; Opie, John, 1761-1807
- H. Tresham, Esqr. R.A. Painted by Opie, engraved by Freeman. Published by Vernor, Hood & Sharpe, Poultry, May 1, 1809., 1809 May 1; engraving; 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1-225)
  Portrait of Henry Tresham.
  Engravings; Tresham, Henry, 1749?-1814
- William Capon. Draughtsman and painter of architecture and landscape to His late Royal Highness the Duke of York. Born 1757-Died 1827. Painted in miniature by W. Bone. Engraved by W. Bond. Published by J.B. Nichols, Parliament Street, March 1, 1828. Gent. Mag. Feby. 1828. p. 105., 1828 March 1; engraving; 22 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1-226)
  Portrait of William Capon.
  Engravings; Capon, William, 1757-1827
- Untitled portrait of John Wesley., undated; engraving; 15.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 1-230)
  Engravings; Wesley, John, 1703-1791
- Gavin Hamilton. Painter. Skirving Pinx. R. Scott Sculps. Published by J. Anderson July 10th 1793., 1793 July 10; engraving; 15.5 x 11 cm. (Box 1-232)
  Portrait of Gavin Hamilton.
  Engravings; Hamilton, Gavin, 1723-1798
- Letter to publisher Thomas Cadell., undated; Cecil, Henry, 1754-1804; 1 page; 7 x 12.5 cm. (Box 1-232)
  Asking him to send Coxe's travels by the bearer, adding 'it was presented to the King last Wednesday.' 14 May. (Referring to one of the many volumes of travels by William Coxe, 1748-1828).
  Correspondence; Coxe, William, 1747-1828
- John Stowe, Historian & Antiquary (From His Monument in the Church of St. Andrew, Undershaft.) Published May 10, 1792 by N. Smith No. 18 Gt. Mays Buildings St. Martins Lane., 1792 May 10; engraving; 25.5 x 19.5 cm. (Box 1-235)
  Portrait of John Stow with text. ' "John Stowe, who was bred a Taylor, quitted his occupation to pursue his beloved study of the History and Antiquities of England, to which he had an invincible propensity. He was not only indefatigable in searching for ancient authors and MSS of all kinds relating to English History, but was also at the pains of transcribing many things with his own hand. As his studies and collections engrossed his whole attention, he in a few years found himself in embarrassed circumstances, and was under a necessity of returning to his trade, but was enabled by the generosity of Arch Bishop Parker to resume his studies. His principal works are his survey of London: a book deservedly esteemed his additions to Hollenshed's Chronicle and his Annals, the folio Volume, commonly called Stowe's Chronicle, was compliled from his papers after his decease, by E. Howes, our author Stowe had a principal hand in two improved editions of Chaucers works, published in this reign on 5 April 1605 AE SO" see Granger p. 269 & Pennants London'.
  Engravings; Stow, John, 1525?-1605
- Charles Towneley. From a Bust by Nollekens in the possession of John Towneley Esqr. T. Baxter delt. Worthington sculp., undated; engraving; 19 x 12 cm. (Box 1-238)
  Portrait of Charles Townley.
  Engravings; Townley, Charles, 1737-1805
- Letter to Mrs. (Mary) Nollekens., 1804 June 4; Townley, Charles, 1737-1805; 1 page; 19 x 11 cm. (Box 1-238)
  Saying that he will have the pleasure of showing 'his collection of old Marbles' to her and her company tomorrow.'
  Correspondence; Nollekens, Mary, 1742 or 3–1817
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1829 August 20; Hills, Ph.; 1 page; 20 x 13 cm. (Box 1-239)
  Referring to his mention of Zoffany's print of Townley's gallery ('I have just read with great pleasure your publication of "Nollekens and his times'), and asking if and when it will be finished.
  Correspondence; Townley, Charles, 1737-1805; Zoffany, Johann, 1733-1810; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833
- Thomas Astle Esqr. F.R.S.&c. Trust. Brit. Mus. & Keeper of the Records in the Tower. European Magazine. Pub. by J. Sewell Cornhill Nov. 1 1802., 1802 November 1; engraving; 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1- 240)
  Portrait of Thomas Astle.
  Engravings; Astle, Thomas, 1735-1803
- Printed receipt signed to Mr. (Richard Paul?) Jodrell, for d'Hancarville's Antiquités étrusques, grecques et romaines. Dated 27 Otre 1768., 1768 October 27; Hancarville, Pierre d', 1719-1805; 1 page; 11 x 8 cm. (Box 1-240)
  For two volumes of his work on Greek and Roman antiquities. Torn with loss.
  Receipts (financial records); Jodrell, Richard Paul, 1745-1831
- British Museum. New Building. Plate 23 Vol. 3 No. 16 of Ackermann's Repository of Arts & Published April 1, 1810 at 101 Strand, London., 1810 April 1; hand colored engraving; 18 x 13.5 cm. (Box 1-243)
  Interior view of the British Museum.
- Envelope fragment addressed to Lady Wodhouse from Cawdor dated February 4 1805., 1805 February 4; 1 page 7.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 1-243)
- Francis Chantrey, Esq. R.A. Engraved by Thomson, from a Painting by Raeburn., undated; engraving; 15 x 9.5 cm. (Box 1-245)
  Portrait of Francis Chantrey.
  Engravings; Chantrey, Francis, Sir, 1781-1841
- Calling card: Mr. Townley, Park St. Westr. No. 7. W. Skelton del. ct Sculp., undated; engraving; 7.5 x 10.5 cm. (Box 1-246)
  Engravings; Visiting cards; Townley, Charles, 1737-1805
- Homer. After an ancient terminus in Mr. Townley's collection, dug up near Baia, 1780. Drawn by E.E. Burney. Engraved by Ls. Shiavonetti., undated; engraving; 16.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 1-246)
- Bust of Charles Townley., undated; engraving; 20.5 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1-247)
- References to the figures in Hogarth's Enthusiasm Delineated. A. After Raphael. B. After Rubens. C. After Rembrandt. D.E.F.G.H. Are imitations of other painters. *From sketches by Hogarth on the margins of the original prints. Published by John Ireland No. 3 Poets Corner Palace Yard Westminster. March 16 1796., 1796 March 15; engraving; 21 x 14 cm. (Box 1-249)
- Front face of an envelope (?) addressed to "Mess. Greenwood & Co., Craig's Court, London". Signed, in lower left corner, Mangin (i.e. Edward Mangin?), of Dublin Carth. Dated July seven 1824., 1824 July 7; Mangin, Edward, 1772-1852; manuscript note; 7 x 12 cm. (Box 1-252)
- Envelope fragment addressed to Mrs. J. Pease dated April 18 1822., 1822 April 18; 1 page; 8 x 15 cm. (Box 1-255)
- Elgin Gallery. Published by Hurst, Robinson & Co. London 1825. Drawn by Mackenzie. Engraved by Chas. Heath., engraving; 12 x 19 cm. (Box 1-256)
  View of the Elgin Marbles, British Museum.
  Engravings; Elgin marbles; British Museum
- Earl of Mansfield. Westminster Abbey., undated; engraving; 11 x 7 cm. (Box 1-258)
  Engraving of the burial monument of William Murray, in Westminster Abbey.
  Engravings; Murray, William, 1705-1793; Westminster Abbey
- St. Paul's (interior). Admiral Earl Howe, Cuthbert, Lord Collingwood, Lieut. Genl. Sir Ralph Abercrombie, Lieut Genl. Sir John Moore. Drawn by H. West. Engraved by J. Shury. London. Published by W.S. Orr. 1833., engraving; 12 x 22 cm. (Box 1-260)
  Five interior views of St. Paul's Cathedral.
  Engravings; St. Paul's Cathedral (London, England)
- Interior of St. Paul's. Engraved by Hobson from a drawing by J.P. Neale for the Beauties of England & Wales., undated; engraving; 15 x 10 cm. (Box 1-260)
  View of St. Paul's Cathedral.
- Samuel Whitbread Esqr. M.P. London Published by J. Asperne Cornhill 1st January 1813. Painted by Opie. Engraved by T. Blood., 1813 January 1; engraving; 15 x 11 cm. (Box 1-264)
  Portrait of Samuel Whitbread.
  Engravings; Whitbread, Samuel, 1764-1815
- Manuscript excerpt: The proper officer at the foreign post office [signed] S. Whitbread, Lombard Street., undated; Whitbread, Samuel, 1764-1815; 1 page; 6 x 11 cm. (Box 1-264)
- Envelope fragment from Samuel Whitbread., undated; Whitbread, Samuel, 1764-1815; 1 page; 6.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 1-264)
- Abbey Church, Bath. European Magazine. Published by J. Sewell, Cornhill. Febr. 1st 1797, 1797 February 1; engraving; 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1-267)
  View of Bath Abbey.
  Engravings; Bath Abbey (Bath, England)
- Antonio Canova, procédé de A. Collas, undated; medal engraving; 30 x 24 cm. (Box 1-266)
  Medal engraving of Antonio Canova.
  Engravings; Canova, Antonio, 1757-1822
- I. Northcote Esq. R.A. Prince Hoare belt., undated; engraving; 12 x 9 cm. (Box 1-269)
  Portrait of James Northcote.
  Engravings; Northcote, James, 1746-1831
- Letter to Joseph Nollekens., 1770 September 15; Welch, Anne; 3 pages; 22.5 x 16.5 cm. Torn at end with loss of signature. (Box 1-270)
  Describing art collecting in Italy. 'By my last 8th inst. I have you an account of what I had done about the Basso rilievos; the Nobleman was really as good as his word, and he spoke both to the Cav. Nani and his brother, but they won't dispose of them, as they are determined to form a sort of gallery, and put all the antique and pictures in good order.' Welch mentions Lord Bute and asks for news of the Royal Academy in London, discusses the journey back to France and England ('if there is no danger of corsairs you may make it [the journey from Carara to Genova] by sea, as I did, in only twelve hours'). She finishes by listing a number of spelling mistakes Nollekens made in his last letter.
  Correspondence; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823
- Henry Constantine Jennings, Esr. Chelsea. E. Dorrell ft. Published by E. Evans, 1 Great Queen Street, Lincoln's Inn Fields., undated; engraving; 21 x 14 cm. (Box 1-271)
  Portrait of Henry Constantine Jennings.
  Engravings; Jennings, Henry Constantine, 1731-1819
- Benjamin West, Esqr. President of the Royal Academy of London: Dedicated to the Directors of the British Institution. W.J. Newton, Pinxt. C. Heath, Sct., undated; engraving; 28 x 19 cm. (Box 1-274)
  Portrait of Benjamin West.
  Engravings; West, Benjamin, 1738-1820
- John Flaxman. From the original picture by John Jackson, in the possession of the Right Hon. Lord Dover. Engraved by R. Woodman. Under the Superintendance of the Society for the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge. London, Published by Charles Knight, Pall Mall East., undated; engraving; 22 x 14 cm. (Box 1-277)
  Portrait of John Flaxman.
  Engravings; Flaxman, John, 1755-1826
- Envelope fragment to the Right Honorable N. Vausittais., undated; 1 page; 7.5 x 16 cm. (Box 1-273)
- Rich. Westmacott. J. Derby pinxt. Thomson sculp., undated; engraving; 16.5 x 13 cm. (Box 1-286)
  Portrait of Richard Westmacott.
  Engravings; Westmacott, Richard, Sir
- Envelope fragment from Richard Westmacott to Wm. Upoctt Esq., London Institution., undated; Westmacott, Richard, Sir; 1 page; 11.5 x 17 cm. (Box 1-286)
  Upcott, William, 1779-1845
- Sir Thomas Lawrence. (Late President of the Royal Academy.) Painted by Charles Landseer. Engraved by Jas. Thomson. London. Library of the Fine Arts 1831., engraving; 20.5 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1-287)
  Portrait of Sir Thomas Lawrence.
  Engravings; Lawrence, Thomas, Sir, 1769-1830
- Letter to John Thomas Smith., 1828 September 6; Eardley-Wilmot, John, Sir, 1783-1847; 2 pages; 23.5 x 18 cm. (Box 1-292)
  Arising out of the biography of Nollekens and about works of art. Mentions a medal by Pisano (i.e. Pisanello?), giving a description and asking if the Museum has a copy.
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Pisanello, 1395-circa 1455
- Letter to Charles Bedford., undated; Roberts, Barré Charles, 1789-1810; 3 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box 1-295)
  Discussing pictures, in particular a print of Holbein's painting of Henry VIII delivering their charter to the company of Barber-Surgeons. Ealing, Saturday night.
  Correspondence; Holbein, Hans, 1497-1543; Bedford, Charles
- Bonaparte. S. lith. de Delpech., undated; lithograph; 21 x 14.5 cm. (Box 1-296)
  Portrait of Napolean Bonaparte.
  Lithographs; Napoleon, Emperor of the French, I, 1769-1821
- Nathaniel Marchant., undated; lithograph; 27 x 20 cm. (Box 1-299)
  Portrait of Nathaniel Marchant.
  Lithographs; Marchant, Nathaniel, 1739-1816
- David Wilkie, Esq. R.A. Engraved by H. Meyer, from an original drawing by J. Jackson. Published July 1, 1815 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1815 July 1; engraving; 31 x 24.5 cm. (Box 1-302)
  Portrait of David Wilkie.
  Engravings; Wilkie, David, Sir, 1785-1841
- Ellis Gamble, goldsmith at the Golden Angel in Cranbourn-Street, Leicester-Fields. Makes, buys and sells all sorts of plate, rings, and jewels. A.M. Ireland sculp., undated; engraving; 20.5 x 16 cm. (Box 1-303)
  Trade cards (advertising); Goldsmiths -- Great Britain; Gamble, Ellis
- W. Sharpe. London Pubd. for the Proprs. of the European Magazine, by Sherwood, Jones & Co. Paternaster Row, Oct. 1 1824., 1824 October 1; engraving; 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1-304)
  Portrait of William Sharp.
  Engravings; Sharp, William, 1749-1824
- J.K. Sherwin., undated; engraving; 10 x 7 cm. (Box 1-309)
  Portrait of J.K. Sherwin.
  Engravings; Sherwin, J. K. (John Keyse), 1751-1790
- Letter to John Thomas Smith from Thomas Gilliland., 1825 February 7; Gilliland, Thomas, fl. 1804-1816; 1 page; 22.5 x 18.5 cm. (Box 1-311)
  Asking him to receive a party of visitors with favour.
- Marquis of Rockingham. First Lord Commissioner of the Treasury. From an Original Picture. Published May 1, 1802 by Cadell & Davies, Strand., 1802 May 1; engraving; 20.5 x 14 cm. (Box 1-314)
  Portrait of Charles Watson-Wentworth, Marquis of Rockingham.
  Engravings; Rockingham, Charles Watson-Wentworth, Marquis of, 1730-1782
- Joseph Moser Esqr. European Magazine. Engraved by Ridley from an original painting by Drummond. Published by J. Asperne Cornhill 1 Sept. 1803., 1803 September 1; engraving; 21 x 13 cm. (Box 1-323)
  Portrait of Joseph Moser.
  Engravings; Moser, Joseph, 1748-1819
- Letter to J.T. Smith from Thomas Grignion., 1803 November 19; Grignion, Thomas; 3 pages; 23 x 18 cm. (Box 1-330)
  Inviting him to see his Italian pictures and English miniatures. Discusses the painter Jan Griffier (the elder). Not the letter quoted in the printed text opposite.
  Correspondence; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; Griffier, Jan, circa 1645-1718
- Letter to Mr Collin., undated; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; 1 page; 10 x 19 cm. (Box 1-334)
  "Mr. Nollekens requests that Mr. Collin will pay a quarters rent that wwas due at Xmas last for a house in his occupation on or before Wednesday next twelve o'clock at noon."
- Letter to unnamed man., 1798 December 18; Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823; 1 page; 18.5 x 12 cm. (Box 1-334)
  Regarding a draft for 100 pounds and sending Mrs. Nollekens' good wishes. Written on the verso of a printed communication announcing the next meeting of the Royal Academy for 21 December 1798 at the Free-Mason's Tavern.
- Fragment of envelope, signed Brownlow (i.e. John Cust, 1st Earl Brownlow?), 1829 March 1; Brownlow, John Cust, 1st Earl, 1779-1853; 1 page; 7.5 x 12.5 cm. (Box 1-335)
- Martin Archer Shee, Esq. R.A. Engraved by W.T. Fry, from an original drawing by J. Jackson, Esq. A.R.A. Published Jan. 14, 1817 by T. Cadell & W. Davies, Strand, London., 1817 January 14; engraving; 32 x 24 cm. (Box 1-335)
  Portrait of Martin Archer Shee.
  Engravings; Shee, Martin Archer
- Letter to Charles Ollier., undated; Smith, John Thomas, 1766-1833; 2 pages; 11 x 18 cm. (Box 1-336)
  Regarding Bat Pidgeon's house and Mr. Sheldrake's letter to him on the subject. Bat Pidgeon was the owner of a famous hairdressing salon in the Strand, London.
  Correspondence; Pidgeon, Bat; Ollier, Charles, 1788-1859
- Pietro Aretino. Marchant, editeur. Alliance des Arts., undated; engraving; 31 x 25 cm. (Box 1-338)
  Portrait of Pietro Aretino.
  Engravings; Aretino, Pietro, 1492-1556
- Michel Angelo. Th. Langer 1840., engraving; 28.5 x 22 cm. (Box 1-341)
  Portrait of Michelangelo.
  Engravings; Michelangelo Buonarroti, 1475-1564
- Harvey Christian Combe, Esq. Many years an alderman of London and a representative of that city in Parliament. Painted by A. Pope. Engraved by J. Baker. Gent. Mag. Sept. 1818. Pl. I., p. 201., 1818 September; engraving; 23 x 14 cm. (Box 1-344)
  Portrait of Harvey Christian Combe.
  Engravings; Combe, Harvey Christian, 1752-1818
- Pasquin., undated; engraving; 17 x 12.5 cm. (Box 1-353)
  Engraving of the ancient statue Pasquino.